<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Vineeta 's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://vineetamehta.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://vineetamehta.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-11T15:04:16+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://vineetamehta.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vineeta Mehta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Water Pollution]]></title>
    <link href="http://vineetamehta.github.io/blog/2013/07/01/humans-polluting-the-water/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-01T13:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vineetamehta.github.io/blog/2013/07/01/humans-polluting-the-water</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Water is important for all and all of us know that very well. But do we actually realize its importance.
A day of water shortage makes us realize that perfectly. All living things would die if it weren&rsquo;t for water. We use water for drinking, washing, cleaning, cooking, and growing our food as well as many, many other things
Water is indespensible.</p>

<p>Today water pollution is a major issue. To ensure that we and our world survive we must start caring about it.</p>

<p>When toxic substances enter lakes, streams, rivers, oceans, and other water bodies, they get dissolved or lie suspended in water or get deposited on the bed. This results in the pollution of water whereby the quality of the water deteriorates, affecting aquatic ecosystems. Pollutants can also seep down and affect the groundwater deposits.</p>

<p> It involves the release of toxic substances, pathogenic germs, substances that require much oxygen to decompose, easy-soluble substances, radioactivity, etc. that becomes deposited upon the bottom and their accumulations will interfere with the condition of aquatic ecosystems.</p>

<p>The major sources that lead to water pollution to the following categories:
* petroleum products
* synthetic agricultural chemicals
* heavy metals
* hazardous wastes
* excess organic matter
* sediment
* infectious organisms
* air pollution
* thermal pollution
* soil pollution</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[H2O]]></title>
    <link href="http://vineetamehta.github.io/blog/2013/06/21/new/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-21T00:38:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vineetamehta.github.io/blog/2013/06/21/new</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://vineetamehta.github.io/images/drop.jpg" alt="water drops" /></p>

<p>Water is the most abundant compound on Earth&rsquo;s surface, covering about 70 percent of the planet. In nature, water exists in liquid, solid, and gaseous states.
Pure water (solely hydrogen and oxygen atoms) has a neutral pH of 7, which is neither acidic nor basic.
Water dissolves more substances than any other liquid. Wherever it travels, water carries chemicals, minerals, and nutrients with it.</p>

<p>Facts About Water</p>

<p>Water is the most common substance found on earth.</p>

<p>Of all the earth&rsquo;s water, 97 percent is salt water located in oceans and seas.</p>

<p>Only one percent of the earth&rsquo;s water is available for drinking water.</p>

<p>About two thirds of the human body is water. Some parts of the body contain more water than others. For example, 70 percent of your   skin is water.</p>

<p>The average five-minute shower takes between 25-50 gallons of water.</p>

<p>The average automatic dishwasher uses 9-12 gallons of water while hand washing dishes can take up to 20 gallons.</p>

<p>Seventy-five percent of a tree is water.</p>

<p><img src="http://cnx.org/content/m20229/latest/graphics1.png"></p>

<p>Apart from drinking it to survive, people have many other uses for water. These include:</p>

<p>cooking
bathing
washing clothes
washing cooking and eating utensils; such as billies, saucepans, crockery and cutlery
keeping houses and communities clean
recreation; such as swimming pools
keeping plants alive in gardens and parks</p>

<p>Water is also essential for the healthy growth of farm crops and farm stock and is used in the manufacture of many products.</p>

<p>It is most important that the water which people drink and use for other purposes is clean water. This means that the water must be free of germs and chemicals and be clear.</p>

<p>Water that is safe for drinking is called potable water.</p>

<p>Disease-causing germs and chemicals can find their way into water supplies. When this happens the water becomes polluted or contaminated and when people drink it or come in contact with it in other ways they can become very sick.</p>

<p>Water that is not safe to drink is said to be non-potable. Throughout history there have been many occasions when hundreds of thousands of people have died because disease-causing germs have been spread through a community by a polluted water supply.</p>

<p>One of the reasons this happens less frequently now is that people in many countries make sure drinking water supplies are potable. Water supplies are routinely checked for germs and chemicals which can pollute water. If the water is not safe to drink it is treated. All the action taken to make sure that drinking water is potable is called water treatment.</p>

<h2 align="center">The India Water Week </h2>


<p></p>

<p>Conceptualized and organized for the first time in 2012 by Ministry of Water Resources, the India Water Week is an International Forum for exchange of concepts and technologies for addressing the issues in the field of Water Resources
For more visit <a href="https://www.facebook.com/indiawaterweek.in">https://www.facebook.com/indiawaterweek.in</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visualization]]></title>
    <link href="http://vineetamehta.github.io/blog/2013/06/20/visualization/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-20T22:50:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://vineetamehta.github.io/blog/2013/06/20/visualization</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2> <h2 align="center">A Different Way to Present the Data</h2></h2>

<p> <p> <i>Data Visualization can be a complicated set of processes to learn.</i> Finding the right way to view your data is as much an art as a science.</p>

<p>Visualization is any technique for creating images, diagrams, or animations to communicate a message. Visualization through visual imagery has been an effective way to communicate both abstract and concrete ideas since the dawn of man.Examples from history include cave paintings, Egyptian hieroglyphs, Greek geometry, and Leonardo da Vinci&rsquo;s revolutionary methods of technical drawing for engineering and scientific purposes.</p>

<p><a rel="full-article" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visualization_%28computer_graphics%29">Read on &rarr;</a></p>

<h2>Data visualization</h2>


<p> A term usually covering both information and scientific visualization.  </p>


<p> Visualization today has ever-expanding applications in science, education, engineering (e.g., product visualization), interactive multimedia, medicine, etc. Typical of a visualization application is the field of computer graphics. The invention of computer graphics may be the most important development in visualization since the invention of central perspective in the Renaissance period. The development of animation also helped advance visualization.</p>


<hr />

<h3>Scientific Visualization</h3>


<p><img src="http://visualizing.org/sites/default/files/imagecache/embedded_vis_medium/images/lang4_01_med.jpg"></p></p>

<p> Scientific visualization is the transformation, selection, or representation of data from simulations or experiments, with an implicit or explicit geometric structure, to allow the exploration, analysis, and understanding of the data. Scientific visualization focuses and emphasizes the representation of higher order data using primarily graphics and animation techniques.</p>




<h3>Information Visualization</h3>


<p><img src="http://www.wired.com/design/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/Iris-Ayasdi-660x363.png" border="1"></p>

<p> Information visualization concentrates on the use of computer-supported tools to explore large amount of abstract data. The term &#8220;information visualization&#8221; was originally coined by the User Interface Research Group at Xerox PARC and included Dr. Jock Mackinlay.Practical application of information visualization in computer programs involves selecting, transforming, and representing abstract data in a form that facilitates human interaction for exploration and understanding. Important aspects of information visualization are dynamics of visual representation and the interactivity. Strong techniques enable the user to modify the visualization in real-time, thus affording unparalleled perception of patterns and structural relations in the abstract data in question.</p>




<h3>Infographics</h3>


<p> <img src="http://www.imfromthefutura.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/grd3InfoGraphicFLAT.CROP2_.jpg" border="1">
  <p>A specific sort of genre of visualizations.  Infographics have become popular on the web as a way of combining various statistics and visualizations with a narrative and, sometimes, a polemic.</p></p>

<h3>Visual Analytics</h3>


<p><img src="http://cdn.practicaldb.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Tableau-on-iPad.jpg" border="1"></p>

<p> The practice of using visualizations to analyze data.  In some research, visualizations can support more formal statistical tests by allowing researchers to interact with the data points directly without aggregating or summarizing them.  Even simple scatter plots, when the variables are chosen carefully, can show outliers, dense regions, bimodalities, etc. In fields where the data themselves are visual (e.g., medical fields), visual analytics may actually be the primary means of analyzing data.  The process of analyzing data through visualization is itself studied by researchers in the visual analytics field.</p>




<h3>Product Visualization</h3>


<p><img src="http://www.guilhemvu.com/images/5D1.jpg" border="1"></p>

<p>Product visualization involves visualization software technology for the viewing and manipulation of 3D models, technical drawing and other related documentation of manufactured components and large assemblies of products. It is a key part of product lifecycle management. Product visualization software typically provides high levels of photorealism so that a product can be viewed before it is actually manufactured. This supports functions ranging from design and styling to sales and marketing. Technical visualization is an important aspect of product development. Originally technical drawings were made by hand, but with the rise of advanced computer graphics the drawing board has been replaced by computer-aided design (CAD). CAD-drawings and models have several advantages over hand-made drawings such as the possibility of 3-D modeling, rapid prototyping, and simulation.</p>


<p>Sources: &ldquo;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visualization_%28computer_graphics%29">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visualization_%28computer_graphics%29</a>&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
